<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Home</title>
    <link>https://example.com/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Genetic Regulation of obesity and fat deposition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/research/genereg-obesity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 18:33:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/research/genereg-obesity/</guid>
      <description>A central question in modern human genetics is how to identify the genes that are involved in human disease. This is a challenging topic, as most mutations that cause disease are located in non-coding regions of the genome. These mutations often act by disrupting gene regulators.
Using a combination of statistical genetics and in vitro experiments, our lab identifies and characterizes genes that are involved in obesity, and defines the gene regulatory networks that control weight gain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic inheritance of metabolic health</title>
      <link>https://example.com/research/germline_inheritance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 18:33:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/research/germline_inheritance/</guid>
      <description>Most heritability is caused by direct mutation to the genome of an organism. However, epigenetic changes to the genome, such as repression or activation of certain genes, can pass through the germ cells of an organism and affect their offspring. This kind of heritability, called epigenetic inheritance, may be particularly important.
Our lab, together with the Barres Lab at the University of Copenhagen and the Simpson lab at the University of Sydney, comprise the GECKO consortium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome architecture in disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/research/tad-fusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 18:33:35 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/research/tad-fusion/</guid>
      <description>Recent research has revealed that DNA is in the nucleus in ways that control and direct gene expression. Topologically associating domains, or TADs, are sections of chromosomes that self-segregate. Gene regulators within the TADs regulate genes within the TADs, and often cannot access genes that are outside their TAD.
Therefore, if the boundaries of a TAD are disrupted, there may be severe consequences for the expression of genes in neighboring TADs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic mechanisms of preterm birth</title>
      <link>https://example.com/research/preterm-birth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 18:33:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/research/preterm-birth/</guid>
      <description>Like many human traits, premature birth is a combination of environmental risk factors and genetic predisposition. By examining the genetic risk factors associated with preterm birth, we can identify genes whose mis-regulated expression increases the risk that an invididual person will give birth prematurely.
Our lab has generated gene expression data, epigenomic data, and chromatin interaction data from placental stromal cells. Using these data, we are identifying novel factors which maintain pregnancy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
